Hello, welcome to the next episode of Learn German in Hindi.
Today we are going to
learn the
mode setting of personal pronouns, nominative pronouns. It is
clear that before this you should
know what are nominative positive cases. So I would request you
that if your case
is not clear yet then watch those videos because
if you watch those videos then today's
concept is very clear. So you
will say that personal problem, so we saw
this dress in the first episode, so what are we going to
see today, so today we will put you in its topic,
meaning now see in Hindi, I
am the character but if she also gives me tea, then she did
not give me tea, she gives me tea,
this I means me, why because
I was the indirect object in it.
Similarly, in English, we have Kedar, I am
here, the subject will be my daughter, she loves her,
so will not come with love, she also loves me. Now
it will come with me, why, that in this sentence,
I was the object.
Similar cases exist in German also and
when you use nominative, whether it is small or dietary,
it is according to that.  If you are in Marathi then if
you have a tube then I have added it so
I will use how we see some examples first of all I have
seen I am character spin center player
height right now wheeler land also love me
subject who is there what I am I
am jute so that is why letters are there so what happened
we have seen miss ov limit miss
kal cricket
a movie place with me what do you remember the meaning of chilli don't
you with is so med steve so
what is its typing near so ovis
print minute near simple regular three
sentence remember you concept is with
kedar because I am nominative will lift
chilli because I tell you that too
speedometer because I put it is
clear so similarly visionary you are
within 2 minutes kedar movie love you will
lift di place death movie speed it
is a simple but if it is clear then you will
see a table on the screen now actually
frankly speaking this is for one
in the middle visionary are enough but
in vagina we have to go FD  It is there and under
them on string you will get this mixture, fill in
now the rest will seem very less to you but
we will learn it today, like I have to do with
me, then that also has to do with that,
right, today we are doing the whole serial, so
if you see, I mean its entire team is in the
directive, email, this
thing, this will be the subject and
object, so this is very easy, ji
ka puja, okay, dat it is just a share of it, due to which
its positive ad is just a
medium, then it is easy for a while, the back
portion starting, both of which are
very active parts, these two wires and
then both big and small ji are ji, ji,
house and dat it will be made, though not much, if you are
learning art members,
then every day just do one Roshni and try
three sentences of it, it will become clear to you, if
we make a few sentences then you will get a
little more confidence, Ishq and doon,
we made 3 sentences, we will make the rest of the sentences as well,
now keep looking at this table,
I will play with him with meaning
What has been formed by scolding the oil
in which the team speed limit is this simple
and mishri vegetables are more in Devdas there is
passenger building easy right now I have a lot for
each one for each and this circular that
if you remember then it is exactly opposite to this ji this is
khura CEA I will
remember right now I am loving chilli
we had seen madam hello so what is that
30 divine so why did all those tabs happen so
if you look in it then there is an app
object so you can see it because it is like this so that is why it will be
again so daddy is
clear
that the word he loves oo again what are we all the
Registrar now jet so what will be a glue kunai kunai
and I
play with him I play with him so what is tune
and country's dot see that Nandish speed
limit in the Agyeya there are 5 sentences
so this simple we have already
seen three wickets and these five what you have to do is
just understand this and ping you and one
trainee sentence I love you jo
How will it be I love you in German,
see, I am a metro subject, so I will
use this powder here, you are what is
pocket and I will give you an object, what is
dish, so I love you in German is made as
Limbodi, so period, if you remember this,
if you have done it, if you do it for eight-ten days, then
this concept will become clear to you, it is
very simple, dish, liter, milk, year itself, not at all,
people do not understand it conceptually, that is why
people use it more, I should use it, I should use it,
friend, it happens
tomorrow, just understand the blouse as nominal, so this will
activate you, Mr., there is a deficiency in A A, I
hope you all have understood the concept,
we will meet in the next episode,
thank you.